<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Team on CUDAN Open Lab</title>
    <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Team on CUDAN Open Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Andres</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/andres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/andres/</guid>
      <description>email / andres.karjus@tlu.ee
website / andreskarjus.github.io
twitter / @AndresKarjus
ETIS / ORCID  Dr. Andres Karjus
Senior Research Fellow
School of Humanities
Tallinn University   About
Andres wants to know why and how all languages and cultures keep changing over time. To that end, he makes use of a variety of methods - machine learning applied to large text corpora, computational simulations, and communication experiments with human participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antonina</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/antonina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/antonina/</guid>
      <description>email / antonina.korepanova@tlu.ee
twitter / @toninakorep
ETIS / ORCID  Antonina Korepanova
Junior Research Fellow
Baltic Film, Media and Arts School
Tallinn University   About
Antonina studies cognitive modelling in art education and the usage of cultural data in online art education.
Bio
Antonina is a junior research fellow and a PhD student at Baltic Film Media and Arts school, Tallinn University. Her research interests (cognitive modeling, and the usage of cultural data in online art education) are linked with CUDAN project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hanna</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/hanna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/hanna/</guid>
      <description>email / hjemmer@tlu.ee
ETIS / ORCID  Hanna Jemmer
Junior Research Fellow
Baltic Film, Media and Arts School
Tallinn University   About
Hanna studies how data driven innovation could contribute to competitiveness of smaller legacy media organisations.
Bio
Hanna has a BA degree in Government &amp;amp; Politics from University of Tartu, an MSc degree in European Governance from University of Bristol, and an MA degree in New Media &amp;amp; Digital Culture from University of Amsterdam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ksenia</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/ksenia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/ksenia/</guid>
      <description>email / mukhina@tlu.ee
website / mukhinaks.github.io
twitter / @mukhinaks
ETIS / ORCID  Dr. Ksenia Mukhina
Senior Research Fellow
School of Digital Technologies
Tallinn University   About
Ksenia focuses on studying urban socio-cultural dynamics. She utilizes statistics and machine learning methods to explore attention and perception patterns through social media data.
Bio
Ksenia Mukhina is a Senior research fellow at the CUDAN Open Lab, and she works at School of Digital Technologies at Tallinn University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mar</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/mar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/mar/</guid>
      <description>email / mar.canet@tlu.ee
website / var-mar.info
twitter / @mcanet
ETIS / ORCID  Mar Canet Solà
Junior Research Fellow
Baltic Film, Media and Arts School
Tallinn University   About
Mar explores new methods and interfaces for navigating the latent space of the AI models with artistic research.
Bio
Mar Canet Sola is a junior research fellow at Cudan and PhD student at Tallinn University in the Baltic Film, Media and Arts School(BFM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mark</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/mark/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/mark/</guid>
      <description>email / mark.mets@tlu.ee
ETIS / ORCID  Mark Mets
Junior Research Fellow
School of Humanities
Tallinn University   About
Mark aims to make sense of phenomena related to the cultural other, including homogenization, antagonization, and transmission. His interdisciplinary research brings together methods of cultural data analysis and cultural semiotics.
Bio
Mark Mets is a junior research fellow at CUDAN and a PhD student at the Tallinn University in the School of Humanities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Max</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/max/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/max/</guid>
      <description>email / mxs@tlu.ee
website / schich.info
twitter / @schichmax
ETIS / ORCID  Dr. Maximilian Schich
Professor for Cultural Data Analytics
Baltic Film, Media and Arts School
Tallinn University   About
Maximilian is a multidisciplinary scientist who collaborates towards a systematic understanding of art and culture, using critical and creative aesthetics, qualitative inquiry, quantitative measurement, and computation.
Bio
Maximilian Schich is a Professor for Cultural Data Analytics and the CUDAN ERA Chair holder at Tallinn University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mikhail</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/mikhail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/mikhail/</guid>
      <description>email / mikhailt@tlu.ee
ETIS / ORCID  Dr. Mikhail Tamm
Senior Research Fellow
School of Digital Technologies
Tallinn University   About
Mikhail is a statistical physicist with background in complex networks, random processes, soft condensed matter and biophysics. He is interested in applying the ideas and methods developed in statistical physics to various types of human-generated data.
Bio
Mikhail is a theoretical physicist, he defended his PhD at Moscow State University, for 2 years he was a postdoc at the University Paris Sud in France, and then for many years worked in Moscow, teaching statistical physics and soft condensed matter at Moscow State University, Higher School of Economics and Moscow Physical-Technical Institute.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mila</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/mila/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/mila/</guid>
      <description>email / milaoiva@tlu.ee
website / milaoiva.fi
ETIS / ORCID  Dr. Mila Oiva
Senior Research Fellow
School of Humanities
Tallinn University   About
Mila is a cultural historian enthusiastic about transnational patterns of circulation of knowledge, understandings, and disinformation in different temporal and technological settings.
Bio
Mila Oiva is a cultural historian enthusiastic about identifying patterns of transnational circulation of knowledge and ideas in a long temporal perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tasweer</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/tasweer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/tasweer/</guid>
      <description>email / tasweer@tlu.ee
 Dr. Tasweer Ahmad
Senior Research Fellow
Baltic Film, Media and Arts School
Tallinn University   About
Tasweer is an information scientist who applies computer science, machine learning and AI techniques to solve the complex problems of cultural data analytics, visualization and understanding.
Bio
Tasweer Ahmad has recently completed his PhD in Electronic Information Engineering from South China University of Technology. During his PhD, he studied the problem of human action recognition and developed some methods for recognizing actions in images and video using deep learning techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tillmann</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/tillmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/tillmann/</guid>
      <description>email / tillmann.ohm@tlu.ee
website / arcu-ohm.com
twitter / @tillmannohm
ETIS / ORCID  Tillmann Ohm
Junior Research Fellow
School of Digital Technologies
Tallinn University   About
Tillmann combines vector embeddings, machine learning and network science to develop tools for algorithmic curation and exploration of curatorial possibility spaces of digital collections.
Bio
Tillmann Ohm is an artist and creative technologist with a special focus on complex curatorial systems. He combines network science, machine learning and digital archives with exhibition-making to develop experimental tools for curating art and engaging with cultural artefacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vejune</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/vejune/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/vejune/</guid>
      <description>email / vejune.zemaityte@tlu.ee
website / vejune-zemaityte.com
twitter / @VejuneZem
ETIS / ORCID  Dr. Vejune Zemaityte
Senior Research Fellow
Baltic Film, Media and Arts School
Tallinn University   About
Vejune uses data analysis and visualisation to study creative industries, focusing on cultural and gender diversity in global cinema. Her research is data-driven, interdisciplinary and industry-facing, often performed in collaboration with external partners.
Bio
Dr. Vejune Zemaityte is a Senior Research Fellow in Cultural Data Analytics at the Baltic Film, Media and Arts School (BFM) in Tallinn University, Estonia working as part of the CUDAN Open Lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yan</title>
      <link>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/yan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cudan.tlu.ee/team/yan/</guid>
      <description>email / yan.asadchy@tlu.ee
website / affinity.ee
twitter / @cactus_606
ETIS / ORCID  Yan Asadchy
Junior Research Fellow
School of Humanities
Tallinn University   About
Yan is an interdisciplinary researcher working on the junction of computer science and humanities and implements contemporary digital methods to study digital culture and self-representation on social media platforms.
Bio
Yan is an interdisciplinary researcher who is currently pursuing his Ph.D. in Cultural Data Analytics at the CUDAN Open Lab at Tallinn University in Estonia, under the supervision of Professors Maximilian Schich and Marek Tamm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
